<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Minutia on kieranhealy.org </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/minutia/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Kieran Healy</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) KIeran Healy.</rights>
    <updated>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Milo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2014/05/31/milo</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2014/05/31/milo</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Milo West Miller, born May 21st, 2014. Weighing in at 9lb 3oz. Lots of pictures on &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/carissabyers&#34;&gt;Carissa&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/dealingwith&#34;&gt;my Instagrams&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/14253796604_bb6c3ab6cc_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Milo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lucy and Regret Avoidance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2014/02/18/lucy-and-regret-avoidance</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2014/02/18/lucy-and-regret-avoidance</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/08/13/one-year.html&#34;&gt;Some perspective&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px; margin-bottom: 1em;&#34; src=&#34;http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=1033868237/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/t=1/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://music.sonluxmusic.com/album/son-lux-breakthru-radio-session&#34;&gt;Son Lux (BreakThru Radio Session) by Son Lux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever I need perspective I go find &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/4779129420/&#34;&gt;this photograph&lt;/a&gt;. It is the greatest regret of my life, leaving behind for even one second the daughter who would one month later be taken from me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I go to work these days Lucy says &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Come back. Miss you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; and leans in plaintively for a kiss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I get home from work these days Lucy says &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yay! Daddy home! Best Daddy ever!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact she does this whole thing where she&amp;rsquo;ll exchange endearing exclamations with us:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Mommy ever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best Lucy ever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, best Mommy EVER!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She plays drums and &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/kfxeygIhg4/&#34;&gt;Paper Jamz guitar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She says &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Baby Milo in Mommy&amp;rsquo;s tummy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/DSC_3903.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/DSC_4327-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&#34;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px; margin-bottom: 1em;&#34; src=&#34;http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=72457702/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/t=9/transparent=true/&#34; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://music.sonluxmusic.com/album/we-are-rising-remixed&#34;&gt;We Are Rising - REMIXED by Son Lux&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She eats dinner by 5:30 most days, which means I don&amp;rsquo;t share that meal with my family, a first in our many years of existence. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to fix that. I have responsibilities and stuff, not the least of which is providing for my family. But Lucy and I will often get about a half an hour together in the mornings. I get home from dropping off Penn at school and she intercepts me on my way to the computer or shower and says, &amp;ldquo;Come play my room.&amp;rdquo; Who am I to disobey?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Context</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/12/31/context</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/12/31/context</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I met &lt;a href=&#34;http://one37.net/author/&#34;&gt;Matt Alexander&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.xoxofest.com/&#34;&gt;XOXO&lt;/a&gt; this year. He&amp;rsquo;s been a bit &lt;a href=&#34;https://needlifestyle.com/&#34;&gt;busy&lt;/a&gt;, but at the one other &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/p/hzi6qYHNnt/&#34;&gt;occasion&lt;/a&gt; I ran into him I complimented him on his writing for &lt;a href=&#34;https://needlifestyle.com/&#34;&gt;Need&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;turns out his degree is in English Lit. Then he drops this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world of carefully curated spheres of information and insight, it&amp;rsquo;s all-too-easy for us to feel we&amp;rsquo;re simply abiding by the societal norms dictated by those around us. And yet, with work in technology and startups, the norm need not be incessant work, poor pay, and high expectations. It can quite easily — and, most importantly, sustainably — be responsible work with contextual perspective. That is, the awareness that life beyond the bounds of work can inform and improve even the most complex of business in an ineffably positive manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Building a good business requires hard work and focus, but those are for naught without perspective. Context and perspective are inextricably linked with the virtues of success and competitive advantage, whilst focusing solely upon negativity will prove to be a pathway toward ruinous failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://one37.net/blog/30/12/2013/tidying&#34;&gt;Tidying&lt;/a&gt;. &amp;hellip;go read the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this Christmas downtime I&amp;rsquo;ve been catching up on sleep, reading and organization, barely digging myself out from under a mountain of debt in all three areas. And like Matt I began to emerge from the fog of backlog with some sense of clarity; capable, perhaps, of stringing a few coherent thoughts together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, professionally and perhaps otherwise, I will begin to transition from being measured in primarily quantitative ways (lines of code, money in the bank) to more qualitative ways (wise strategic insights, the character of my family). Of course it&amp;rsquo;s not as if I&amp;rsquo;m suddenly made a transition from young man to old, but circumstances have recently accentuated the transition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s official: I&amp;#39;m too old and have too many real problems to spend any more time hating on Arial.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Miller (@dealingwith) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dealingwith/statuses/411540904021729280&#34;&gt;December 13, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a year when instead of having to explain why my vein-like experience trail&amp;ndash;ventures into writing and the art business, non-profits and music&amp;ndash;don&amp;rsquo;t interfere with my &amp;ldquo;hard&amp;rdquo; coding skills, but rather simply paint the picture of the context the sum of those experiences provide in making right decisions. Not how many questions I answer correctly but how many questions I correctly write. Judged by peers, less by elders&amp;hellip;and finally understanding that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter how much the young hotshots are judging me anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So 2014 begins with aspirations to apply that experience in more ways. Being a better husband and parent. Expressing more gratitude. Having more patience. The usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first step to losing weight is to stop gaining weight.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Jacob Rathe (@JacobRathe) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JacobRathe/statuses/402337546559971328&#34;&gt;November 18, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My physical health is still front-of-mind. Last year I took a 6-month break from alcohol and, no surprise, achieved my lowest weight since college. Since picking back up the sauce, I&amp;rsquo;m back up above my pre-teetotaling weight. People who think I can make other changes to lose that weight underestimate my  affection for beer. Still, it has been wearing off. And no time like the present, especially considering the present is January 1st, famous for people with goals bigger than their wills. In other words, don&amp;rsquo;t offer me booze, and don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if I&amp;rsquo;m a little bit antisocial if your social involves alcohol. I might give myself &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=cheat+day+willpower&#34;&gt;cheat days&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; but I haven&amp;rsquo;t decided yet, so assume I&amp;rsquo;m completely on the wagon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Too much to read. To much to do. To much to learn. To much to teach. To much to watch. To much to sit quietly and think about.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Miller (@dealingwith) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dealingwith/statuses/405152367709913088&#34;&gt;November 26, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2014 will likely be my busiest year to date, and given the number of balls dropped (some of which need to be picked up!) in 2013, that is a little disconcerting. Old enough to know that more work requires more &lt;a href=&#34;http://frankchimero.com/blog/2013/09/the-inferno-of-independence/&#34;&gt;balance&lt;/a&gt;, but young enough to not know how to balance the two just yet. I say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to so many things, how is it I still say &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; to enough things to get me into trouble?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a great email workflow: anything that requires followup I star and archive. Then I wait to revisit starred emails until it&amp;#39;s too late&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Miller (@dealingwith) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dealingwith/statuses/405123737223061505&#34;&gt;November 26, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/lucy_studio.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#39;t know much, but I know this: my daughter&amp;#39;s hair is red.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Miller (@dealingwith) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dealingwith/statuses/401794681538760704&#34;&gt;November 16, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is difficult to describe Lucy in words. We try every day. We blurt out &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re so cute!&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re so perfect!&amp;rdquo;. She&amp;rsquo;s so happy so much of the time. She&amp;rsquo;s bossy in a way that makes you want to do her bidding. She&amp;rsquo;s sensitive to other&amp;rsquo;s feelings, sometimes to a fault. She&amp;rsquo;s caring and wants to take care of others. She&amp;rsquo;s wary of new people, but once she&amp;rsquo;s vetted you she&amp;rsquo;s incredibly hospitable. She wants to cook for you and fix your boo-boos and make you comfy-cozy. She&amp;rsquo;s learning a lot of new words every week. She knows all the words and most of the dance moves to Ylvis&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;The Fox&amp;rdquo; song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Carissa&amp;#39;s babysitter wasn&amp;#39;t available during her shoot this morning. So my morning is What Does the Fox Say on repeat.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Miller (@dealingwith) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dealingwith/statuses/400647952172990464&#34;&gt;November 13, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/penn_lucy_winfrey.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penn &amp;amp; Lucy at Winfrey Point, Dallas, TX&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penn is in the beginnings of that long, awkward transition from boy to man and handling it rather well. He takes his licks like a man. He&amp;rsquo;s a great older brother to Lucy. He is navigating new territory well. Carissa and I are learning how to parent through these complexities as we go. We recently had a difficult experience with the computer and Minecraft (involving his attempts with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Griefer&#34;&gt;griefing&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mod_(video_gaming)&#34;&gt;mods&lt;/a&gt;) which has resulted in some imposed constraints. It took some patience and repetition but we came to a resolution that seems to be holding up. He&amp;rsquo;s very into Minecraft but so am I so it works out. We went to Minecon in Orlando in November with the entire family (which included Disney); I never got a chance to blog about it but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/sets/72157638993354183/&#34;&gt;here are some pictures&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/penn_lucy_portland_condo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penn &amp;amp; Lucy in Portland&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also went as a family to Portland, Austin and Oklahoma (a few times). It was a good year for travel and by no accident. With the new baby boy arriving in May, travel will be all but impossible this year (except the quick trip up to Oklahoma), so 2013 was the year to get it out of our system!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last morning in PDX, Lucy eating a Voodoo donut while wearing a River City Bicycle cap.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Daniel Miller (@dealingwith) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dealingwith/statuses/382138867400196096&#34;&gt;September 23, 2013&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/carissa_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Carissa&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This woman. What a rock. A gorgeous, smart, patient, loyal cornerstone of our family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/baby_boy_miller.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Baby Boy Miller&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baby Boy Miller aka Hugo/Leo/Ezra/Otto is on his way! 2014 promises to be a most exciting and eventful year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanksgiving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/11/28/thanksgiving</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/11/28/thanksgiving</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should not love our kindred alone for their genius and glory, but also for their homely virtues and domestic affections that expanded and flourish unobserved save by the little world in which they moved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/the_descendants_of_capt_thomas_carter.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;The Descendants of Captain Thomas Carter&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the preface to &amp;ldquo;The Descendants of Captain Thomas Carter&amp;rdquo;, a book tracing (some of) my lineage back to the son of a &amp;ldquo;London merchant of good family.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XOXO 2013 (Part 3)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/10/29/xoxo-2013-part-3</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/10/29/xoxo-2013-part-3</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;The final installment of XOXO posts, because a lot has gone on since then I also want to blog about&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An aerial drone view of XOXO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube uf9rrskAV-A %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking drones, Chris Anderson, former editor of Wired, now runs a drone company, delivered the first talk of the festival. Afterwards I was already mentally buzzed and ready to get back to Dallas and do awesome things&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube ZeLF8LTePZI %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first speaker I was really looking forward to was Maciej Cegłowski. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed &lt;a href=&#34;http://idlewords.com/&#34;&gt;his writing&lt;/a&gt; for a long time, and for almost as long a time, his &lt;a href=&#34;https://pinboard.in/&#34;&gt;bookmarking service&lt;/a&gt;. Turns out he is a great speaker as well, and used the writings of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_David_Thoreau&#34;&gt;Thoreau&lt;/a&gt; as a launch point for an inspiring talk about character and authentic living in the modern age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube eky5uKILXtM %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first surprise for me was &lt;a href=&#34;http://jackcheng.com/&#34;&gt;Jack Cheng&lt;/a&gt;, who I had not heard of before. But his honesty about his motivations, process and financial realities immediately endeared me to him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to quit your job and go all in on your art. It&amp;rsquo;s something, that if it&amp;rsquo;s really about self-discovery, it&amp;rsquo;s something that is healing and something that is constantly at work and something you can never do enough of&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube F2gq_0zdmjU %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned Jack Conte in my &lt;a href=&#34;/2013/09/29/xoxo-2013-part-2/&#34;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt;. Here is his talk. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to check out his project for funding artists, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patreon.com/&#34;&gt;patreon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube K9NjntTUJ1Q %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jonathon Coulton, another musician&amp;hellip;with similar themes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn’t want to be ‘sad dad’ with unfulfilled dreams&amp;hellip;Happiness is the only metric you need for judging your success. It’s your boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube xtcjRyoOGIs %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were quite a few really memorable talks&amp;hellip;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/user/xoxofest/videos?view=0&amp;amp;sort=dd&amp;amp;shelf_id=2&#34;&gt;here are all the XOXO talks, for your further discovery and edification&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XOXO 2013 (Part 2)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/29/xoxo-2013-part-2</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/29/xoxo-2013-part-2</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/bump/9879172833/&#34; title=&#34;Sunday! by bump, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2858/9879172833_fbd8c7828e_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sunday!&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rocketcandy/9971867635/&#34; title=&#34;XOXO Festival Conference by rocketcandy, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2863/9971867635_8c7d64f79f_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;XOXO Festival Conference&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotables from XOXO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want you to move here and make me things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Disruption&amp;rsquo;s a great word, it&amp;rsquo;s just been co-opted by a bunch of douchebags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/waxpancake&#34;&gt;@waxpancake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a field across the street full of goats, and now it&amp;rsquo;s full of drones as well. Welcome to Portland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andymcmillan&#34;&gt;@andymcmillan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/rocketcandy/9922818286/&#34; title=&#34;XOXO Festival Conference Day 2 by rocketcandy, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7310/9922818286_3d5afe57b1_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;XOXO Festival Conference Day 2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aww daddy. We probably need to get a goat.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/carissa&#34;&gt;@carissa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Knowing what you&amp;rsquo;re doing is not nearly as important as knowing your values.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MaxTemkin&#34;&gt;@MaxTemkin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only rich people have the luxury of not talking about money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you live a life by your own lights, and follow your principles, maybe once in a while someone will come and bring you a basket of donuts. And it&amp;rsquo;s okay to eat the donuts! They&amp;rsquo;re delicious!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://static.pinboard.in/xoxo_talk_thoreau.htm&#34;&gt;Maciej Cegłowski&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s good to honour examples of success, but we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t worship them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Art, first and foremost, is for the development of the artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to quit your job and go all in on your art. If it&amp;rsquo;s about healing self discovery you can do it lifelong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jackcheng&#34;&gt;@jackcheng&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t work for large companies for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mollycrabapple&#34;&gt;@mollycrabapple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the information superhighway just leads to a convenience store&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ev&#34;&gt;@ev&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mirka23/9959679333/&#34; title=&#34;Boing Boing Panel by Mirka23, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7309/9959679333_53d161d09a_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Boing Boing Panel&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/xeni&#34;&gt;@xeni&lt;/a&gt;:
&amp;gt; Boing Boing&amp;rsquo;s the closest thing to an anarchist collective I&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/doctorow&#34;&gt;@doctorow&lt;/a&gt;:
&amp;gt; Only with fewer meetings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mirka23/9975568626/&#34; title=&#34;Jack Conte by Mirka23, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7386/9975568626_10a0bcd367_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Jack Conte&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jack Conte (above) was my favorite speaker. As such, I did not capture any pithy bits from his talk, enraptured as I was the entire time. Above, he stands in front of a slide depicting the (what would turn out to be slightly maddening) contruction of the set for this video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% youtube mZ02alEkbLw %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to be &amp;lsquo;sad dad&amp;rsquo; with unfulfilled dreams&amp;hellip;Happiness is the only metric you need for judging your success. It&amp;rsquo;s your boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jonathancoulton&#34;&gt;@jonathancoulton&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XOXO is the distillation of everything that&amp;rsquo;s right about indie and maker culture. You can&amp;rsquo;t possibly be interested in what&amp;rsquo;s going on in those communities and come away not ready to dedicate (or re-dedicate) yourself to them. XOXO is a perfect place to be who you are, who you want to be, who you are becoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;but indie culture at large (and I count myself as part of that culture) needs to be able to have open conversations about the risks, consequences and costs of pursuing your dreams… and failing. Not just business failure, not just financial failure, but personal and emotional failure as well. The decisions our dreams inspire have consequences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eod.com/blog/2013/09/talking-about-failure/&#34;&gt;Greg Knauss&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were a lot of #xoxofest talks mentioning personal mental health, right? Didn&amp;rsquo;t expect it but enjoyed the raw vulnerability of it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mathowie/status/382155888116502529&#34;&gt;@mathowie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XOXO 2013 (Part 1)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/28/xoxo-2013-part-1</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/28/xoxo-2013-part-1</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Travel&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_19_6_04_54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy with a sucker&#34; title=&#34;Travel is a little bit better if you have a sucker&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as these things go, I thought my family did very well with the actual-travel portions of our Portland trip this year. (Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/09/23/xoxo/&#34;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post, in case you weren&amp;rsquo;t aware this has become an annual event.) The only hitch was when we arrived very late to Portland and were met with the &lt;em&gt;worst&lt;/em&gt; domestic car rental experience I have ever endured. Whatever you do, never rent from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yelp.com/biz/advantage-car-rental-portland#hrid:oj7pmES5lP4-TtjNWtMX9g&#34;&gt;Advantage Car Rental&lt;/a&gt;; they are terrible. I made the mistake of not checking out their horrible Yelp reviews prior to booking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XOXO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_11_16_18.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;XOXO entrance&#34; title=&#34;XOXO entrance&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://2013.xoxofest.com/&#34;&gt;XOXO&lt;/a&gt; will require its own post but overall I enjoyed it more than last year. The speakers were once again excellent but for some reason the &amp;ldquo;theme&amp;rdquo; that evolved over the course of the three days seemed more real and practicable than last year. I talked to more people this year which was another plus. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t stress about the parts I missed in the evenings. I just enjoyed my time in Portland with my family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_11_08_50.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;XOXO Market&#34; title=&#34;XOXO Market&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_11_20_16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy and Penn outside XOXO day 1&#34; title=&#34;[Lucy and Penn outside XOXO day 1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were goats across the street, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/urbangoatspdx&#34;&gt;they&lt;/a&gt; were &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23xoxofest%20goats&amp;amp;src=typd&#34;&gt;a hit with just about everyone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_12_05_40.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Goats!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_12_06_11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;More goats!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first day of XOXO was pretty free-form, so I took the oportunity to hang out with my friend Scott, and we all went to a food truck pod for grilled cheeses inside a double decker bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_1_24_30.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy and Penn in the double decker bus&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later we had to drive back to the airport to exchange our rental car (more of the terrible experience) after which we went straight to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gobytram.com/&#34;&gt;arial tram&lt;/a&gt;, after which we hung out in the coffee shop at the bottom and played in a fountain in a nearby park. I like how my family can have fun pretty much anywhere. We enjoy the simple things in life, and Portland provides a great platform for that enjoyment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_20_4_47_07.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy happy at the coffee shop&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day during the lunch break I rode to River City Bicycles and enjoyed some free espresso and finally got a shop cap for my collection (last year they didn&amp;rsquo;t have any).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_21_3_38_04.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;River City Bicycles&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the family did some shopping as well, Lucy fits in well aesthetically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_21_6_27_54.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy shopping&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And before we had to leave, the kids had their Voodoo Doughnuts and Salt and Straw ice cream. We know what&amp;rsquo;s up, Portland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_22_10_31_31.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy and Penn eating at Voodoo Doughnuts&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/Portland/Sep_22_7_18_29.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy eating ice cream at Salt and Straw&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelmed by Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/10/overwhelmed-by-management</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/10/overwhelmed-by-management</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5535/9720057139_84e1ae7284_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shelf of things&#34; title=&#34;I&#39;m not sure what this photo has to do with this post, but I like it. It&#39;s a shelf in my late grandfather&#39;s shop. He was one of those people who really did seem to have everything together&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow in the last 9-10 months I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from managing (seemingly) almost nothing to managing (seemingly) &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. This had made me feel very old. Like somehow one hits some age where one looks around and realizes &lt;em&gt;no one is in control here&lt;/em&gt; and instead of continuing about one&amp;rsquo;s life one &lt;em&gt;takes control&lt;/em&gt;. And it all feels very overwhelming. I am now in a job with more responsibility (which, yea!), part (most?) of which is managing (three! just three people! it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much of my time). I manage the family finances. I plan and execute vacations. I am producing and releasing a record (&lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more work&amp;ndash;when you&amp;rsquo;re doing it entirely on your own&amp;ndash;than most people realize). I am managing a Minecraft server for a handful of 9 year old boys (which, &lt;em&gt;OMFG!&lt;/em&gt;). I organize a &lt;em&gt;weekly bike ride&lt;/em&gt; from a &lt;em&gt;Facebook group&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to form into a &lt;em&gt;proper road bicycle club&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d like to actually &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; more than once a month! My &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instapaper.com/&#34;&gt;read later&lt;/a&gt; queue, for goodness sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could go on for a while. With increasing levels of disbelief, frustration and rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not only the things I&amp;rsquo;m directly involved in. Carissa manages the children&amp;ndash;a whole pile of different things from &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; (ha!) care-taking to schedules to meals to sport team logistics to doctor appointments&amp;ndash;as well as her photography career and volunteering and her list also goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point being it&amp;rsquo;s all a little overwhelming and just staying on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=ubiquitous%20capture&#34;&gt;capturing&lt;/a&gt; everything that needs done is hard enough, let alone keeping up the energy to keep chipping away at the list! My &lt;em&gt;really good days&lt;/em&gt; are those where I feel like everything has at least been captured, that I&amp;rsquo;m not forgetting some major thing that is going to mess up everything that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; on a list. That I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed some deadline that is going to cost my family a lot of money or drama or &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like they say, &lt;em&gt;there has to be a better way!&lt;/em&gt; But&amp;hellip;is there? Do those people I see in fancy online videos really have &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; shit &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; together? Do my friends with no children, no mortgage, no &lt;em&gt;significant&lt;/em&gt; other understand the &lt;em&gt;embarrassment of riches&lt;/em&gt; they enjoy in terms of their own time, attention and opportunities? The older and more experienced I get the more I understand the answer to that question is &lt;em&gt;no they definitely do not&lt;/em&gt;. I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in there lies the rub. &lt;em&gt;Loneliness&lt;/em&gt; takes its toll as well. It can precipitate many bad, time-consuming choices. &lt;em&gt;Too many&lt;/em&gt; opportunities, or at least the ability to take them, spreads one too thin, and often one does a multitude of mediocre things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure there are the exceptions we all aspire to be. The &lt;em&gt;overachievers&lt;/em&gt;. But I bet they have their &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; too, either now or in the future. And we just don&amp;rsquo;t know about it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3752/9602471902_bf23b853b8_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucy remains amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ve missed so much in terms of documenting said amazingness on this blog. But she plays the drums, holds impromptu dance parties, is affectionate, opinionated, demanding and just so darn cute no one can even stand it, and I keep double checking my own prejudice against 3rd party exclamations of the same!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/lucy_drums.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy drums&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Seriously, just go &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/carissabyers&#34;&gt;follow my wife on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sobriety Spell Stay</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/07/20/sobriety-spell-stay</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/07/20/sobriety-spell-stay</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My six months of sobriety technically ended last Wednesday but I&amp;rsquo;m in what I&amp;rsquo;m referring to as &amp;ldquo;penalty time&amp;rdquo;.{% fn_ref 1 %} And like penalty time in a soccer match, the imminence of the end makes the next week{% fn_ref 2 %} just feel like a long Friday. Or that part of summer camp where all the kids are getting picked up but you&amp;rsquo;re one of the last few to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I intended to add additional weight-reducing and (hopefully) happiness-increasing behaviors throughout the six months but failed at every other attempt. I blame the amount of will power it has taken to not drink. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that the lack of cellular interest{% fn_ref 3 %} will result in a dramatic decrease in alcoholic intake compared to where I left off six months ago. Even if only to keep these extra ten pounds I lost off! I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that allowing myself the freedom to drink will allow for some will power to be spread across other beneficial behaviors.{% fn_ref 4 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those behaviors include meditation, sleep improvement, core strength conditioning, diet improvement. We&amp;rsquo;ll see what I can do. I&amp;rsquo;ve been incredibly busy lately. Work isn&amp;rsquo;t overwhelming but it certainly requires some extended hours. And Lucy&amp;rsquo;s at a perfect age that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss a blink of. Between those two factors and normal &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo; stuff, I barely have time to ride just a few hours a week, and my weight has been creeping back up despite the alcohol-free lifestyle. None of those three can be changed, really, so I do what I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I did notice during this time was the experience of very lucid happiness. I mentioned &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2013/02/04/weeks-seven/&#34; title=&#34;I’ve been fighting clinical depression for over two years while taking dose after dose of depressives most every night. Pretty f**king stupid.&#34;&gt;before&lt;/a&gt; that not blocking my anti-depressants was one of my motivations and sure enough, it seemed to work. For sure, I want to be careful to not indulge enough to counteract the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made in that area. I&amp;rsquo;m on a path to get off the medications, which of course I would like to do.{% fn_ref 5 %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% footnotes %}
  {% fn I &amp;ldquo;slipped up&amp;rdquo; about 5 times over the 6 months. Two of those were towards the beginning and I look back at those with bemusement at this man who couldn&amp;rsquo;t imagine a life without &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; alcohol. Two were more recently and they were both incredibly anti-climatic. Like, &amp;ldquo;Wow, that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enjoyable at all. Weird.&amp;rdquo; %}
  {% fn I am officially having a few drinks with friends in celebration next Friday. The date had as much to do with scheduling the get-together as it did with serving some additional time for transgressions. %}
  {% fn Of course I&amp;rsquo;m referring to addiction but I&amp;rsquo;m hesitant to use that term due to the fact that almost everyone who uses that term finds their condition to be permanent and requiring of intense treatment. They also probably found their condition to profoundly effect their daily life in a very destructive way. I did not see myself in that camp, but I could see the writing on the wall if I continued unconstrained. %}
  {% fn Yeah, did you know willpower is a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ego_depletion&#34;&gt;limited resource&lt;/a&gt;?) %}
  {% fn And of course distance from &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/&#34;&gt;past events&lt;/a&gt; is also of a great benefit in that area. %}
{% endfootnotes%}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/06/23/catch-up</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/06/23/catch-up</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Almost two months since my last blog post. Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy. I&amp;rsquo;m also looking to change, yet again, how/where I publish my blog and kept thinking I would get around to that change before I posted again, but alas&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Follow Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2013/03/13/the-rumors-of-google-readers-death-have-not-been-greatly-exaggerated/&#34;&gt;RSS reader of choice&lt;/a&gt;, current: &lt;a href=&#34;http://feedly.com&#34;&gt;feed.ly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to stop &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2013/04/26/busy-busy-busy-still/&#34;&gt;playing Minecraft&lt;/a&gt; due to a developing &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Repetitive_strain_injury&#34;&gt;RSI&lt;/a&gt;. (The game, like all first person games, involves a lot of mouse moving.) I miss it almost as much as I miss real beer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked about my six month &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2013/02/17/weeks-ten-and-eleven/&#34;&gt;sobriety&lt;/a&gt; since the end of month one, apparently. It&amp;rsquo;s gone ok. I&amp;rsquo;ve slipped up but certainly haven&amp;rsquo;t been tempted to cut it short or slipped back into the habit. I am, however, counting the weeks left (I&amp;rsquo;m in month six now). I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to monitor myself carefully when I do start drinking again. I&amp;rsquo;m concerned about the amount of desire still left for the sauce but confident lifting the restrictions will be anticlimatic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Lucy: 17 Months&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s actually almost 19 months old now, but&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3832/8893978262_2bb2bd784c_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy, 17 months&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2013/05/lucy-17-months.html&#34;&gt;17 months&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2013/06/arboretum-with-lucy.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2860/8979523159_1f68c9c690_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy at the Dallas Arboretum&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She is like a beacon of unending emotions of all kinds. The complexities of how I feel when I look at her is too much for words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7414/8980186586_fcdbeab950_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy at the Arboretum&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2872/8893952612_dfc67c2df8_c.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy and Penn&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She&amp;rsquo;s re-completed our family. She is a force. &amp;ldquo;LOOK AT ME. I WILL NOW MELT YOUR HEART.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/9110594256/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7437/9110594256_3cee643c5e_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy holding a picture of Margot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday while Carissa was cleaning out some of the stuff from the attic Lucy found a picture of Margot and carried around the house, talking about the cute baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;PA Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needs its own post. It was great. There was some bad news delivered while we were there. Life can&amp;rsquo;t help but be complicated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;From the podcast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/johnnycitizen/116961&#34;&gt;From&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.merlinmann.com/roderick/ep-67-all-of-the-small-beer.html&#34;&gt;Roderick on the Line&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% audio &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnycitizen.com/podcast/jcp_16.mp3&#34;&gt;http://johnnycitizen.com/podcast/jcp_16.mp3&lt;/a&gt; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/johnnycitizen/114253&#34;&gt;From&lt;/a&gt; Palahniuk&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Haunted-A-Novel-Chuck-Palahniuk/dp/1400032822&#34;&gt;Haunted&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% audio &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnnycitizen.com/podcast/jcp_15.mp3&#34;&gt;http://johnnycitizen.com/podcast/jcp_15.mp3&lt;/a&gt; %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Telling a story is how we digest what happens to us,” Mr. Whittier says. “It’s how we digest our lives. Our experience.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You digest and absorb your life by turning it into stories,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other events–the ones you can’t digest–they poison you. The worst parts of your life, those moments you can’t talk about, they rot you from the inside out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the stories you can digest, that you can tell–you can take control of those past moments. You can shape them, craft them. Master them. And use them to your own good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are stories as important as food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are stories you can use to make people laugh or cry or sick. Or scared. To make people feel the way you felt. To help exhaust that past moment for them and for you. Until that moment is dead. Consumed. Digested. Absorbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Currently&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experiencing a 24-48 hour period of exteremely low energy. This happens to me about once a quarter and I find it extremely frustrating. So I&amp;rsquo;m blogging&amp;hellip;slowly. Carissa says I should just roll with it. I want to be able to get an instant blood test and find out what&amp;rsquo;s wrong. Maybe this time it&amp;rsquo;s just the Summertime Blues. It&amp;rsquo;s not even that hot yet and I&amp;rsquo;m suffering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But overall I&amp;rsquo;m lost in a veil of Okayness. I&amp;rsquo;m ok with so much. Nothing surprises me anymore. I get frustrated with small things but the big things are all alright with me. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m getting old. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve yet to figure out what my one Big Project is. I&amp;rsquo;m wondering if that&amp;rsquo;s all just a story we tell ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
