<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Bicycling on kieranhealy.org </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/bicycling/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Kieran Healy</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) KIeran Healy.</rights>
    <updated>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2012 Festive 500</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/12/31/the-2012-festive-500</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/12/31/the-2012-festive-500</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;{% img left /images/rapha-festive-500-2012-v1-100.jpg Festive 500 Complete badge %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rapha.cc/the-festive-500--2012&#34;&gt;It&lt;/a&gt; was harder than &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/01/01/rapha/&#34;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; but I managed it. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure why it was harder except for the fact that it was consistently 10-30 degrees colder than it was last year, but that just made it feel more authentic. I also rode my second-ever century (&lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/10/23/century.html&#34;&gt;the first&lt;/a&gt;) on many roads I&amp;rsquo;d never ridden on before, which was painful but left me with a great feeling of accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Day One&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;http://app.strava.com/runs/33816261/embed/3b6afdd57200c5a61c00b13ce152c45afee2af2e&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolled with the Oak Cliff crew I frequently ride with. Some new roads for me in an area I ride frequently, and the best weather of the entire 500.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Day Two (Christmas day)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8351/8307306663_8ed8b63e10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Leaving for the snowy Christmas day ride&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got Penn a new bike for Christmas so he was anxious to get on it. Unfortunately it was raining all morning (I&amp;rsquo;ve never opened presents to the sound of thunder before). As soon as the rain turned to snow in the afternoon we headed out. The additionally unfortunate part was that there were 20+mph winds. Penn made it over two miles before he asked to turn around. Pretty good I thought. We were both miserable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That night&amp;rsquo;s Christmas dinner was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/8308288565/in/photostream&#34;&gt;an amazing time with friends&lt;/a&gt; that deserves its own blog post but will probably be reserved for our oral history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Day Three&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day after Christmas was again really cold (for Texas), and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anyone willing to ride in the sub-30°F weather. I managed a measely 20 miles in the morning, then Penn and I went out again in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8360/8331679728_61c164fb6c_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Taking a break&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8357/8311356325_4473e2d1b8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Showing Penn how to true a wheel&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8073/8312492646_309ef1b2cd.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penn at the Spillway on a cold ride&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8493/8331287210_99d6a0b050.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ice sickles&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Day Four&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;http://app.strava.com/runs/34296639/embed/ee4ae2aace71ad7fabe0c5a9e1ccc82d756c0434&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rolled out with the Oak Cliff crew again, this time led by a local road/cyclocross racer of repute. The temperature never rose above 40°F. The ride, that was originally planned to be &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; 80 miles turned into 100+ not-slow miles to places further south than I have ever ventured on a bicycle. Beautiful roads, lots of dogs, lots of dirt roads, horses that ran beside us, interesting architectural sights (&lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/6Z1bJRES&#34;&gt;like this old abandoned strip mall?&lt;/a&gt;), and lots of pain. Sadly no pictures, we were too busy riding, eating, or keeping our hands inside our winter gloves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Day Five&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recovery day from the previous day&amp;rsquo;s century, I only rode two laps around White Rock Lake, thankfully running into some friends who made the short, cold miles go a little bit faster. Later in the afternoon I took Penn to go climbing with our new friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://coachstewartball.com/&#34;&gt;Stewart&lt;/a&gt; and some of the kids he coaches. Penn&amp;rsquo;s pretty good at climbing so it is fun to watch him scale increasingly difficult routes. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out a way to get him into it more seriously. We have two more climbing days scheduled for this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8503/8330637081_45883e2ae8_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penn&#39;s a natural climber&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Day Six&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;http://app.strava.com/runs/34618857/embed/5b003fe8e209918b11b86c18b34236731c579863&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not really recovered but knowing I needed to complete the 500 kilometers over the next two days due to a 100% chance of rain on the final day of the Festive, I set about cranking out the final miles as gracefully as possible. Ended up with a group of four that again helped keep the pace up and the miles tick by faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Day Seven&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe height=&#39;405&#39; width=&#39;590&#39; frameborder=&#39;0&#39; allowtransparency=&#39;true&#39; scrolling=&#39;no&#39; src=&#39;http://app.strava.com/runs/34838041/embed/546673b452cdc524a0cd7fdb1c914d8b1dcfd8f4&#39;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My final day I was on my own for only the second time since starting the 500. Heading north with a south wind meant a long, slow, windy return trip, then one final lap around the lake to finish the required kilometers. I ended up at 501.7 kilometers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Day Eight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I am grateful to not be on my bike, but also grateful for all the miles inspired by the challenge. It&amp;rsquo;s been raining all day. We had breakfast with some friends, Lucy took a long nap, and now we&amp;rsquo;re hanging out with some more friends. Life is good as our little family marches forward into 2013. Buoyed by past heartache, we bob along on the swells of our daily joys, finding our way across this sea of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8502/8268595956_9115748c10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy in my hat&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8364/8327226031_9a0664a67b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy is amazing&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bicycling as an Aesthetic and Ascetic Pursuit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/07/21/bicycling-as-an-aesthetic-and-ascetic-pursuit</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/07/21/bicycling-as-an-aesthetic-and-ascetic-pursuit</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smashred/7302666568/in/faves-dealingwith/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7228/7302666568_cf537411be_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Jered Gruber&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original title of this post when I started it almost six months ago was &amp;ldquo;Strava and the continued douchification of bicycling&amp;rdquo;. But since then &lt;a href=&#34;http://allthingsd.com/20120619/gps-app-strava-sued-over-cyclists-death/?refcat=news&#34;&gt;enough has been said&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;a href=&#34;http://strava.com&#34;&gt;Strava&lt;/a&gt; and I actually like Strava quite a bit except for the stupid{% fn_ref 1 %} segments. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid the real problem is the way cycling seems to attract a certain type of person with not just a lack of character, but a lack of basic appreciation for the beauty of our world or other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, I think, is a factor of approaching the sport not just from a competitive standpoint, but one that actually opposes what I would consider a more honorable way: that of riding a bicycle as an aesthetic, and ascetic, pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized that many of my posts about cycling have to do with this aesthetic. &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/09/corner.html&#34;&gt;Turn&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/07/super-bowl.html&#34;&gt;Super Bowl&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/02/20/ride.html&#34;&gt;When in Doubt, Ride Hard&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/03/07/bikes.html&#34;&gt;Hell, Let&amp;rsquo;s Keep Talking About Bikes&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/07/16/dear-fellow-recreationalists.html&#34;&gt;Dear Fellow Recreational&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/26/yapab.html&#34;&gt;Yet Another Post About Bicycling&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/09/27/leroica.html&#34;&gt;L&amp;rsquo;Eroica&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/01/01/rapha/&#34;&gt;The 2011 Festive 500&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smashred/7433130290/in/faves-dealingwith/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8014/7433130290_0a65f374f9_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Jered Gruber&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead of putting more words to the topic, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d just share some more examples. Thing is, even though as I recently observed with some friends, &amp;ldquo;Bike racing attracts a certain kind of douchebag,&amp;rdquo; it&amp;rsquo;s not really about racing or not racing. It&amp;rsquo;s about the central Thing. If that Thing is numbers or ego, then the aesthetic is likely lost. If it is about man, machine and motion, well, that&amp;rsquo;s a better start. A desire not just for the attainable win, but for the ever-ellusive &lt;a href=&#34;http://redkiteprayer.com/2011/04/souplesse/&#34;&gt;souplesse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smashred/7482309840/in/faves-dealingwith/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8024/7482309840_0be02f2560_o.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Jered Gruber&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways to understand the aesthetic of which I speak is through photography. One of my favorite photographers in this genre is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smashred/&#34;&gt;Jered Gruber&lt;/a&gt;. He was kind enough to allow me to use some of his photographs in this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smashred/7307320178/in/photostream&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8146/7307320178_605f843cb4_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Jered Gruber&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another group of people who get this, despite being some of the fastest people in the world, are those of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slipstreamsports.com/&#34;&gt;Garmin-Sharp-Barracuda&lt;/a&gt; professional cycling team. They had a sub-par Tour de France; both their leaders crashed out of the race; although they still later won a stage in dramatic fashion. Here are some highlights from just a month ago, when things were going much better:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/E7LvOvo1G5E&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Impossible Hour (or skip to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eiKACH4v9LU&amp;amp;t=3m20s&#34;&gt;the really good part&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/eiKACH4v9LU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Sunday in Hell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/cWTj6H2KKr4?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bicycling.com/blogs/theselection/2012/01/20/i-dont-train/&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Train&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t even use a computer or speedometer or anything anymore, unless I’m going way out of the Lehigh Valley and figure I’ll want to use a Garmin to find my way home eventually. Sometimes even then, though, I just wing it. I like the idea of winging it. Of being something on the wing. I like that better than knowing how long I spent in zone five.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% footnotes %}
  {% fn As opposed to reasonable segments, like hill climbs. %}
{% endfootnotes%}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>So I raced for the first time in 15 years today</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/05/28/so-i-raced-for-the-first-time-in-15-years-today</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/05/28/so-i-raced-for-the-first-time-in-15-years-today</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7218/7292344158_c57fe1f567_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Carissa Byers&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn&amp;rsquo;t go so bad. I finished. I was doing ok until about 2 laps to go when I had that sudden feeling like all the blood was running out of my head and I watched the pack of riders disappear up the road in front of me. I actually did not know how many laps were left so when I came across the start/finish line by myself and saw the 2 laps remaining sign I also realized that I was going to finish the race w/o being lapped/pulled or otherwise not finishing. So there was that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn&amp;rsquo;t as stressful or rewarding as I had hoped. I wish I had dug deeper and managed to stay with the peleton for the duration. I will probably do it again, but I&amp;rsquo;m not chomping at the bit like I thought I would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing is going to compare to the experiences I had growing up, racing as a junior (under 18) on my team in Pennsylvania; or my first seasons on the track in Trexlertown, or my first climb to the top of Mt Lemmon in Tucson. Those were unique in a way I could not appreciate at the time. Perhaps I can try to recreate them; and certainly I feel a particular kind of &lt;strong&gt;sympatico&lt;/strong&gt; with my fellow riders, especially some with whom I train semi-regularly. Somehow, though, it feels a lot like a band: a particular set of people in a particular set of circumstances that happens with or without the efforts of human intervention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7076/7292346024_da47bd0a7d_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Carissa Byers&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7232/7292347444_6ebc286998_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by Carissa Byers&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Awesome Easter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/04/08/pretty-awesome-easter</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/04/08/pretty-awesome-easter</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/04/ride_map.png&#34; alt=&#34;/files/2012/04/ride_map.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;managed to crawl out of bed in time to make the morning ride and I never regret it when I do. I pieced together a few different routes and we ended up with a really pleasant &lt;a href=&#34;http://app.strava.com/rides/6404927&#34;&gt;54 miles&lt;/a&gt;. The temperature was pretty perfect (about 70F), the legs felt good, clouds protected us from the Texas sun (now they&amp;rsquo;re watering our [still] parched land, which makes me even happier to have gotten a ride in early) and there were no flats or any other types of trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/04/lucy_smile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;/files/2012/04/lucy_smile.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got home Lucy was all smiles and chatty, too. She&amp;rsquo;s becoming more delightful by the day. I sat on the kitchen floor and soaked it in while I ate and drank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/04/tomination.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;/files/2012/04/tomination.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I watched Tom Boonen dominate Paris-Roubaix on the DVR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have to work. Hopefully that doesn&amp;rsquo;t ruin everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guilt, Mortality and Peace: The 2011 Festive 500</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/01/01/guilt-mortality-and-peace-the-2011-festive-500</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/01/01/guilt-mortality-and-peace-the-2011-festive-500</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/01/festive.png&#34; alt=&#34;Rapha Festive 500 Logo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Guilt&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rapha.cc/festive-500&#34;&gt;Rapha Festive 500&lt;/a&gt; is a worldwide challenge to ride 500km from the 23rd to the 31st of December. (Rapha makes very nice cycling garments as well as &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/05/26/yapab.html&#34;&gt;those cool videos I post all the time&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/01/09/corner.html&#34;&gt;Last year it was the impetus for my return to regular cycling&lt;/a&gt; and the kickoff to a year filled with thousands of miles, new friends, lost pounds and a new appreciation for the further reaches of both my abilities and the town in which I reside. Last year I did not complete the 500km. This year I was determined to have a proper go of it despite the constraints of having a new baby in the house and the obvious schedule issues around the holidays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/01/klein_0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;My trusty steed&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As expected the rides were cold, often wet, mostly long (one must average about 40 miles per day) and as such engender an increased &lt;a href=&#34;http://tomsoutham.blogspot.com/2011/12/constitution.html&#34;&gt;constitution&lt;/a&gt; and determination to ride regardless of conditions. This, as I see it, is really the biggest advantage of the challenge. Sure, for some, the distance is laughable and many participants complete it in &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; worse conditions; but for me it is the perfect distance at the perfect time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was struck with a strange emotion one dark morning. Here I was slogging away on my bicycle for no real reason except some number thrown down&amp;ndash;by a brand, no less&amp;ndash;while my new beautiful baby was at home. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t guilt, really, but a serious questioning. Why do we do this? Why do we throw leg over saddle day after day? I don&amp;rsquo;t race; sure, I&amp;rsquo;d like to lose a few more pounds; but really? This?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A mysterious love for the bike and its culture seemed at odds with the obvious and deeply powerful love for Lucy and my family. I started riding again for the sake of my sanity. Now was it leading me into a new kind of delusion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/01/matt_c_0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Photo by @mactionnews&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up finishing the 500km with a day to spare&amp;ndash;entirely thanks to meeting &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/mactionnews&#34;&gt;Matt Christensen&lt;/a&gt; on the trail that day. He rode &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagr.am/p/dnXLp/&#34;&gt;877km&lt;/a&gt; total in some kind of godlike rush of determination and a true appreciation for the joy of riding a bike. The day I met him he rode a century&amp;ndash;his second of the week. I joined him for a portion of that century&amp;ndash;enough to cross the 500km mark with a few kilometers to spare. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/31875579&#34;&gt;23&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/31961179&#34;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/32037230&#34;&gt;25&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/32102193&#34;&gt;26&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/32237316&#34;&gt;27&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/32312578&#34;&gt;28&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/32375339&#34;&gt;29&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.endomondo.com/workouts/32479151&#34;&gt;30&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Mortality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The afternoon after completing the 500 Carissa and I were on the way to the doctor when we witnessed a most horrific thing. A girl, who couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been older than 15, stepped into the street and was struck by a car. I must presume she died instantly. I was one of the first people on the scene and I could tell almost immediately. The images burned into my brain that day are going to haunt me for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many emotions, so many lives forever changed, so much grief and hurting to be experienced, my own understanding of all that still&amp;ndash;always&amp;ndash;too close.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And fear. Cars are our constant enemy when we ride our bikes. Their speed, their mass, the careless way their drivers move them around the city. Today was my first ride on the road since then, and every intersection, every passing car evoked those images, that fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Peace&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/01/penn_0.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penn Smith&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penn has taken a recent and enthusiastic renewed interest in cycling. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if the 500 had anything to do with it, but yesterday he begged and begged to go on a ride with me, and it was nice, having completed the challenge, to not worry about how long a ride would be. Little did I know we would end up riding a complete loop of White Rock Lake, no small feat for an eight year old&amp;ndash;not to mention the number of pedal strokes required by the gear ratio on his small single speed bike! As we rode slowly along the trail, he chatting away, me constantly instructing him if only to assuage my own concerns, a peace eventually came to visit. The weather was perfect. I was spending time with my stepson doing something I enjoy, and he shared unadulteratedly in that joy. I had a beautiful family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The loop around White Rock is about 15km from our house and back, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t count those kilometers. At least not with a cyclometer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
