<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Life on kieranhealy.org </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/life/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Kieran Healy</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) KIeran Healy.</rights>
    <updated>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daddy&#39;s Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/11/06/daddys-girls</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/11/06/daddys-girls</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/8142180676/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8471/8142180676_2c28de05c0_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About two years ago Daniel went to work and our late daughter, Margot, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/4779129420/&#34;&gt;crawled to the door crying&lt;/a&gt; because she didn&amp;rsquo;t want him to go. Last week &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/8142181422/in/set-72157631896701414/&#34;&gt;Lucy did the same thing&lt;/a&gt;.  I grabbed my camera because in that moment, everything in my head stopped and connected the two moments together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has happened a lot, recently. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because Lucy is finally nearing an age where we are ripe with memories of Margot and the similarities are beautiful. And now tragic. Lucy just started crawling and she shares the bizarre crawl of her sister. One leg out and one leg under in an awkward scoot. They share the same tone of whine for things. They share physical items and it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see things like the car that my Aunt Gyl got Penn when he was 4 months old, that Margot loved, that Lucy now pushes around with her one little outstretched finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucy&amp;rsquo;s stunning red hair is defiantly different and I love her for it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Lucy approaching her first birthday I am consumed with remembering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2012/11/daddys-girls.html&#34;&gt;Daddy&amp;rsquo;s Girls&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/10/07/nic</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/10/07/nic</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I found out &lt;a href=&#34;http://hauntedgeographies.typepad.com/&#34;&gt;Nic Hughes&lt;/a&gt; lost his ongoing fight with cancer. He was a loved husband, father, friend, designer and thinker. He was barely older than I. He was a peer and an idol at once. After Margot&amp;rsquo;s death he wrote me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Daniel,
I think we’ve briefly met once and have occasionally exchanged email and comments from time to time. I talked to Steve at Greenbelt and he confirmed what I suspected from your twitter feed&amp;ndash;that Margot did not make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no way of understanding this or coming close to your experience, apart from, that I have kids too. In the end, words are completely inadequate. This is to show solidarity and say that I’m thinking of you in this unfathomable moment of loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this is not too invasive? Take care,
Nic Hughes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home from the office, where I was when I heard, I was somehow drawn to memories of a host of those we&amp;rsquo;ve lost. I found myself listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carteralbrecht.com/&#34;&gt;Carter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s record. I happened to drive by where earlier this year we saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/01/01/rapha/&#34;&gt;a teenage girl killed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, in reply to my helpless email of remorse, our mutual friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kesterbrewin.com/&#34;&gt;Kester&lt;/a&gt; replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From afar, with the dignity and rage with which you dealt with your loss, you&amp;rsquo;ve already been such a help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to conceive of the fact that my own suffering gives space for others&amp;rsquo;, but I guess it is true. While I cannot create a narrative that accounts for our loss of Nic&amp;hellip;while I only recently, in a moment of personal reflection, discounted all narratives that gave meaning to our loss of Margot&amp;hellip;in it lies a bit of something that provides some meaning to others. As I discovered today, Nic once wrote me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narrative is gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amen to that, and godspeed, Nic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smallfire.org/vaux_gifted.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is something I recorded for Nic (as requested of many by his friends before his passing). It might give you a little insight into what Nic meant to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;/files/Nic.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about the things I mention in that audio, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smallfire.org/vauxpage1.html&#34;&gt;Vaux&amp;rsquo;s page on smallfire.org&lt;/a&gt; or explore &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vaux.net/services-archive&#34;&gt;Vaux&amp;rsquo;s archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
