<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Weeknotes on kieranhealy.org </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/weeknotes/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Kieran Healy</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) KIeran Healy.</rights>
    <updated>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Six</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/01/13/week-six</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jan 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/01/13/week-six</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Carissa asked what the titles of these posts were about. In case you also do not know, they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;a href=&#34;http://weeknotes.com/&#34;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;updates about what your business has been doing over the past seven days or so.&amp;rdquo; In this case I don&amp;rsquo;t have a &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; yet but I&amp;rsquo;m simply counting from when I begin exploring new ideas and options following the end of my time at Extra Sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also I just discovered, somewhat pleasantly, that I had counted incorrectly last week and that this is in fact week six and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2013/01/05/week-six/&#34;&gt;last week&lt;/a&gt; was week five, even though the permalink will forever hold my mistake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sundays is when Penn&amp;rsquo;s extreme extraversion and 9-year-oldness most conflicts with my extreme introversion and old-manness. 36 hours of he not being around enough people and me being around too many people. We both start to lose our minds in subtle but important ways and conflict is the frequent result; of course being the adult I am the one who must swallow my emotions and just deal with it. This whole thing is normally assuaged by the fact I go on long bike rides weekend mornings, but the last few weeks the very cold weather and other schedule conflicts have prevented those rides from happening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smbc-comics.com/index.php?db=comics&amp;id=2854&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.smbc-comics.com/comics/20130113.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last week I intended to start working away from home at a coworking facility. The lack of focused time has brought progress on this project to a standstill. Being at home, I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered Lucy will devour all present persons&amp;rsquo; attention. It often seems like even with two of us here it is all we can do to get in a shower and check email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although you must admit, she is very cute. And you haven&amp;rsquo;t even seen her turn pages in a cookbook and say &amp;ldquo;MMMmmm!&amp;rdquo; every time there is a picture of food!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8325/8361171269_2927a048e8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy loves cookbooks&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also had a rather busy social schedule as of late, both personal and business related. Making up for a little lost time in that department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But part of that for me is the return of paid work, possibly turning full time in as few as two weeks. This is a good thing, says my budget and bank account, which are tired from months of redness. But it makes me a little regretful for having not taken better advantage of this time for my own ends, even if the better part of me knows this new thing is a long term process that might be better served constrained to a couple hours in the early mornings and evenings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then there is the reality of all the other things that need doing, from personal care like riding my bike and reading to family matters such as medical issues and home repairs. I&amp;rsquo;m preaching to the choir here I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new record has been one of the highlights in regards to the last month&amp;rsquo;s productivity. It is nearly done. It even has a name, or I should say some variations on a name. I&amp;rsquo;ll be sure to reveal more as it becomes ready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fitness has been another story. Since completing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/12/31/the-2012-festive-500/&#34;&gt;Festive 500&lt;/a&gt; I have not done much but gain weight. I&amp;rsquo;ve had some persistent back pain while riding since the last two days of the 500 that I thought would go away with some rest but hasn&amp;rsquo;t. I&amp;rsquo;ve been terrible at doing core work (because I hate it) but apparently that fact has caught up with me and now I&amp;rsquo;m faced with a long fight to regain some core strength and rid myself of this pain. It&amp;rsquo;s also continued to be cold, which I love, but I must have burnt myself out on being out in it because my motivation to ride seems to dive the closer to 40°F it gets, and lately it&amp;rsquo;s been that or below. (Like most people, I suppose, I find there to be a pretty solid bell curve of comfort between 40 and 100.) It did get above 60 one day last week, and I managed a quick ride with only armwarmers for extra warmth. By the next day, though, the temperature had dropped and a very cold rain set in. Texas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week Five</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/01/05/week-five</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/01/05/week-five</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;*Update: &amp;lsquo;This was originally titled &amp;ldquo;Week Six&amp;rdquo; but I&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been 100% less work done than planned. There has been Christmas, and lots of bicycle riding, and breakfasts, and dinner parties, and small tasks, and time with Penn and Lucy, and both of them being amazing in their own ways. And my wife, who I am so grateful for and who holds everything together with cuddles and baked goods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8472/8349716591_3b25b8a01f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy in my bicyle caps&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record, Lucy loves bicycles and bicycle paraphernalia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some ideas about what this new year should hold for me in terms of growth and better personhood. There have been a few first steps in the direction of those ideas. Nothing worth writing about just yet. But hope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8335/8350404500_e34ce5b981.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy play and breakfast&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record, I make a mean scrambled eggs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quietly, the week before last, a few days after Christmas, Lucy grew older than Margot was. Before she left us, Margot was walking. Lucy isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly close, but she&amp;rsquo;s making progress towards bipedalism. When remembering, there is a certain measure of cognitive dissonance, when the last weeks of Margot&amp;rsquo;s life are mostly a blur of pain and disbelief; and, well, all weeks with Lucy are so full of joy, laughter and happiness. I recently saw Penn playing with a three year-old and it was impossible not to imagine what it would be like to have Margot still here with us. But we don&amp;rsquo;t. We do have each other. And the four of us continue forward in a cloud of that grace and we will be grateful for every day it exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8497/8338364111_5d08a360af.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Penn climbing&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record, Penn is a kick-ass climber. See that taller wall to his right? He reached the top of it, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new record is almost done. It might have a title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, listen to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;100&#34; style=&#34;position: relative; display: block; width: 400px; height: 100px;&#34; src=&#34;http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/v=2/track=2059444882/size=venti/bgcol=FFFFFF/linkcol=4285BB/&#34; allowtransparency=&#34;true&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://noahgundersen.bandcamp.com/track/honest-songs&#34;&gt;Honest Songs by Noah Gundersen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
