<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Thoughts on kieranhealy.org </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/thoughts/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Kieran Healy</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) KIeran Healy.</rights>
    <updated>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sonder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2014/06/26/sonder</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2014/06/26/sonder</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.vimeo.com/video/80318195?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;color=ffffff&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/80318195&#34;&gt;Sonder | The Dictionary of Obscure Sorrows&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/user7278324&#34;&gt;John Koenig&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sonder &amp;ndash; &lt;em&gt;n.&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; the realization that each random passerby is living a life as vivid and complex as your own—populated with their own ambitions, friends, routines, worries and inherited craziness—an epic story that continues invisibly around you like an anthill sprawling deep underground, with elaborate passageways to thousands of other lives that you’ll never know existed, in which you might appear only once, as an extra sipping coffee in the background, as a blur of traffic passing on the highway, as a lighted window at dusk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was introduced to this word and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dictionaryofobscuresorrows.com/post/23536922667/sonder&#34;&gt;The Dictionary of Obscure Sorrows&lt;/a&gt; today by someone 20 years younger than I. This person is a very smart person and part of a group of very smart people I have the privilege of employing as part of my &lt;a href=&#34;http://minecraftu.org/&#34;&gt;Minecraft U&lt;/a&gt; staff. These people are also very empathetic and of particularly good character. They are good humans, connecting deeply both intellectually and emotionally with their world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They give me hope for the future, and teach me new things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overwhelmed by Management</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/10/overwhelmed-by-management</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2013/09/10/overwhelmed-by-management</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5535/9720057139_84e1ae7284_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Shelf of things&#34; title=&#34;I&#39;m not sure what this photo has to do with this post, but I like it. It&#39;s a shelf in my late grandfather&#39;s shop. He was one of those people who really did seem to have everything together&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow in the last 9-10 months I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from managing (seemingly) almost nothing to managing (seemingly) &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;. This had made me feel very old. Like somehow one hits some age where one looks around and realizes &lt;em&gt;no one is in control here&lt;/em&gt; and instead of continuing about one&amp;rsquo;s life one &lt;em&gt;takes control&lt;/em&gt;. And it all feels very overwhelming. I am now in a job with more responsibility (which, yea!), part (most?) of which is managing (three! just three people! it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; much of my time). I manage the family finances. I plan and execute vacations. I am producing and releasing a record (&lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; more work&amp;ndash;when you&amp;rsquo;re doing it entirely on your own&amp;ndash;than most people realize). I am managing a Minecraft server for a handful of 9 year old boys (which, &lt;em&gt;OMFG!&lt;/em&gt;). I organize a &lt;em&gt;weekly bike ride&lt;/em&gt; from a &lt;em&gt;Facebook group&lt;/em&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to form into a &lt;em&gt;proper road bicycle club&lt;/em&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;d like to actually &lt;em&gt;blog&lt;/em&gt; more than once a month! My &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instapaper.com/&#34;&gt;read later&lt;/a&gt; queue, for goodness sake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could go on for a while. With increasing levels of disbelief, frustration and rage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And not only the things I&amp;rsquo;m directly involved in. Carissa manages the children&amp;ndash;a whole pile of different things from &amp;ldquo;basic&amp;rdquo; (ha!) care-taking to schedules to meals to sport team logistics to doctor appointments&amp;ndash;as well as her photography career and volunteering and her list also goes on and on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point being it&amp;rsquo;s all a little overwhelming and just staying on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=ubiquitous%20capture&#34;&gt;capturing&lt;/a&gt; everything that needs done is hard enough, let alone keeping up the energy to keep chipping away at the list! My &lt;em&gt;really good days&lt;/em&gt; are those where I feel like everything has at least been captured, that I&amp;rsquo;m not forgetting some major thing that is going to mess up everything that &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; on a list. That I haven&amp;rsquo;t missed some deadline that is going to cost my family a lot of money or drama or &lt;em&gt;even more&lt;/em&gt; time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like they say, &lt;em&gt;there has to be a better way!&lt;/em&gt; But&amp;hellip;is there? Do those people I see in fancy online videos really have &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; shit &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; together? Do my friends with no children, no mortgage, no &lt;em&gt;significant&lt;/em&gt; other understand the &lt;em&gt;embarrassment of riches&lt;/em&gt; they enjoy in terms of their own time, attention and opportunities? The older and more experienced I get the more I understand the answer to that question is &lt;em&gt;no they definitely do not&lt;/em&gt;. I certainly didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in there lies the rub. &lt;em&gt;Loneliness&lt;/em&gt; takes its toll as well. It can precipitate many bad, time-consuming choices. &lt;em&gt;Too many&lt;/em&gt; opportunities, or at least the ability to take them, spreads one too thin, and often one does a multitude of mediocre things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure there are the exceptions we all aspire to be. The &lt;em&gt;overachievers&lt;/em&gt;. But I bet they have their &lt;em&gt;thing&lt;/em&gt; too, either now or in the future. And we just don&amp;rsquo;t know about it yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3752/9602471902_bf23b853b8_z.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucy remains amazing. I&amp;rsquo;ve missed so much in terms of documenting said amazingness on this blog. But she plays the drums, holds impromptu dance parties, is affectionate, opinionated, demanding and just so darn cute no one can even stand it, and I keep double checking my own prejudice against 3rd party exclamations of the same!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/lucy_drums.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Lucy drums&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Seriously, just go &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/carissabyers&#34;&gt;follow my wife on Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Today is a Wonderful Day</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/11/12/today-is-a-wonderful-day</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/11/12/today-is-a-wonderful-day</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;to (ride a bike) (write a blog) (take the train) (eat bacon)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First there was &lt;a href=&#34;2012/09/23/xoxo/&#34;&gt;XOXO&lt;/a&gt; and its admonishment to &amp;ldquo;Work on something you are passionate about, because if it becomes successful you&amp;rsquo;ll have to do it all the time.&amp;rdquo; Then there was &lt;a href=&#34;2012/09/30/bret-victor-inventing-on-principle/&#34;&gt;Bret Victor&amp;rsquo;s talk on &amp;ldquo;Inventing on Principle&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. Then there was &lt;a href=&#34;2012/10/07/nic/&#34;&gt;the news&lt;/a&gt; that Nic Hughes had lost his fight with cancer. Then there was &lt;a href=&#34;2012/11/06/daddys-girls/&#34;&gt;an acknowledgement&lt;/a&gt; of the similarities between Margot and Lucy and the moment I&amp;rsquo;ve described as my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/4779129420/&#34; title=&#34;About two years ago Daniel went to work&#34;&gt;biggest regret&lt;/a&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s been a serious theme around here and it&amp;rsquo;s not going to stop with this post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Nic&amp;rsquo;s Memorial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nic&amp;rsquo;s memorial was last weekend and my friend Steve Collins attended and documented some of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smallritual/8173359539/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8349/8173359539_02eb6d830f.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;balloons&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his Flickr I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/smallritual/8175797068/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;these words&lt;/a&gt;, penned by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kesterbrewin.com&#34;&gt;Kester Brewin&lt;/a&gt; for the event:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We gather in protest&lt;br /&gt;
in defiance of the absurd and arbitrary cruelty of illness&lt;br /&gt;
and say that we will not be cowed&lt;br /&gt;
that, though we should not be here&lt;br /&gt;
now that we are we will raise our hearts&lt;br /&gt;
in glad remembrance of a truly wonderful man&lt;br /&gt;
and raise our voices in loud song&lt;br /&gt;
against the silence of the grave&lt;br /&gt;
and raise our glasses in merry rebellion&lt;br /&gt;
against that which comes without thought&lt;br /&gt;
and takes those we love from us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In response to the experience, &lt;a href=&#34;http://smallritual.blogs.com/small_ritual/2012/11/in-memoriam.html&#34;&gt;Steve wrote&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;nic&amp;rsquo;s death is a warning. we always think we can meet up some other time - when we&amp;rsquo;re less busy [but we&amp;rsquo;re always busy]. and suddenly there is no more time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the same busyness claims the time we should have been doing the stuff we were placed here to do - our unique contribution or gift. instead we shopped and cleaned and cooked, made trivial phone calls, worked for money, in the hope that when we&amp;rsquo;d done all these acts of maintenance they would give us time and space for what we really meant to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;How You Will Die&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to top it off, Deliberatism (one of my favorite blogs, probably now to become one of your favorites if you take the time to read some of the archive) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deliberatism.com/editorial/how-you-will-die/&#34;&gt;reminds us&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like so many things in life, we complicate matters by treating edge cases as high probabilities, while skipping the obvious (and easy to remedy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news? By leaving work early, walking home the long way, and enjoying a good dinner, you’re taking direct action against public enemy number one. Isn’t it a pleasant surprise to find a remedy so appealing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately for us, Nic and Margot were both taken from us too soon and in unlikely ways. Nic&amp;rsquo;s cancer was exceptionally rare, and I still struggle with the number of unlikely events that led to our loss of Margot. To say it has raised my anxiety and made me particularly prone to &amp;ldquo;treating edge cases as high probabilities&amp;rdquo; is putting it lightly. But the additional good news is that the treatment is still the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Cycling&amp;rsquo;s part of that subtle end of the spectrum.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my main prescriptions is bicycling. Over in &lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/johnnycitizen&#34;&gt;my podcast&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;rsquo;ve recently posted two clips of Mike Burrows from &lt;a href=&#34;http://thebikeshow.net/burrows-on-the-bicycle-part-one/&#34;&gt;The Bike Show&lt;/a&gt;, which has this to say about him:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mike Burrows is probably best known for his design of the Lotus 108 pursuit bike that Chris Boardman rode in the Barcelona Olympics, winning the first gold medal for a British cyclist in over 70 years. But Mike has made a huge contribution to pedal powered machines more widely. His compact road frame first developed for Giant is now a design standard and his designs have moved the world of laid back or recumbent bicycles on from the early, pioneering days in 1970s California. Burrows remains inventive, opinionated and passionate about bicycles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/johnnycitizen/88559&#34;&gt;first clip&lt;/a&gt; is about the freedom that a bicycle engenders, both a freedom in movement but also a freedom from toil:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://johnnycitizen.com/podcast/jcp_09.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://huffduffer.com/johnnycitizen/90965&#34;&gt;second clip&lt;/a&gt; is about money and happiness:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://johnnycitizen.com/podcast/jcp_10.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;So I write this while at work. With a little bit of irony.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://distilleryimage2.s3.amazonaws.com/c44ac14e2c3011e281cb22000a1f9a0a_7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;bacon&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Penn and I had a day together. First we went to Cindy&amp;rsquo;s for a 2nd breakfast. Then we hung out at the office for a while; I completed a couple of tasks and he read his book report book. Then we walked to the train, took the train to Mockingbird station, had a drink and a bite at Trinity Hall, shopped at Urban Outfitters (a dress for mom, a hat and a gag gift for Penn), took the train back downtown and drove home, making a quick stop for ice cream. He was perfect the entire afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is just the &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/11/29/desire-and-meaning.html&#34;&gt;usual&lt;/a&gt;, a post about meaning and &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com/2011/11/07/worst-day.html&#34;&gt;more&lt;/a&gt; ruminating about how it might be staring me in the face the entire time. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m just having a midlife crisis. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ve never really been able to distinguish between the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Things_First_(book)&#34;&gt;important and the merely urgent&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Maybe I should just go home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Later, at home&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;and maybe I should just keep writing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daddy&#39;s Girls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/11/06/daddys-girls</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/11/06/daddys-girls</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/8142180676/in/photostream/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8471/8142180676_2c28de05c0_b.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About two years ago Daniel went to work and our late daughter, Margot, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/4779129420/&#34;&gt;crawled to the door crying&lt;/a&gt; because she didn&amp;rsquo;t want him to go. Last week &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/8142181422/in/set-72157631896701414/&#34;&gt;Lucy did the same thing&lt;/a&gt;.  I grabbed my camera because in that moment, everything in my head stopped and connected the two moments together&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has happened a lot, recently. I think it&amp;rsquo;s because Lucy is finally nearing an age where we are ripe with memories of Margot and the similarities are beautiful. And now tragic. Lucy just started crawling and she shares the bizarre crawl of her sister. One leg out and one leg under in an awkward scoot. They share the same tone of whine for things. They share physical items and it&amp;rsquo;s fun to see things like the car that my Aunt Gyl got Penn when he was 4 months old, that Margot loved, that Lucy now pushes around with her one little outstretched finger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lucy&amp;rsquo;s stunning red hair is defiantly different and I love her for it&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Lucy approaching her first birthday I am consumed with remembering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://carissabyers.blogspot.com/2012/11/daddys-girls.html&#34;&gt;Daddy&amp;rsquo;s Girls&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/10/07/nic</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/10/07/nic</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I found out &lt;a href=&#34;http://hauntedgeographies.typepad.com/&#34;&gt;Nic Hughes&lt;/a&gt; lost his ongoing fight with cancer. He was a loved husband, father, friend, designer and thinker. He was barely older than I. He was a peer and an idol at once. After Margot&amp;rsquo;s death he wrote me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Daniel,
I think we’ve briefly met once and have occasionally exchanged email and comments from time to time. I talked to Steve at Greenbelt and he confirmed what I suspected from your twitter feed&amp;ndash;that Margot did not make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no way of understanding this or coming close to your experience, apart from, that I have kids too. In the end, words are completely inadequate. This is to show solidarity and say that I’m thinking of you in this unfathomable moment of loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this is not too invasive? Take care,
Nic Hughes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way home from the office, where I was when I heard, I was somehow drawn to memories of a host of those we&amp;rsquo;ve lost. I found myself listening to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.carteralbrecht.com/&#34;&gt;Carter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s record. I happened to drive by where earlier this year we saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/01/01/rapha/&#34;&gt;a teenage girl killed&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, in reply to my helpless email of remorse, our mutual friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kesterbrewin.com/&#34;&gt;Kester&lt;/a&gt; replied:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From afar, with the dignity and rage with which you dealt with your loss, you&amp;rsquo;ve already been such a help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to conceive of the fact that my own suffering gives space for others&amp;rsquo;, but I guess it is true. While I cannot create a narrative that accounts for our loss of Nic&amp;hellip;while I only recently, in a moment of personal reflection, discounted all narratives that gave meaning to our loss of Margot&amp;hellip;in it lies a bit of something that provides some meaning to others. As I discovered today, Nic once wrote me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Narrative is gold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amen to that, and godspeed, Nic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smallfire.org/vaux_gifted.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/space.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is something I recorded for Nic (as requested of many by his friends before his passing). It might give you a little insight into what Nic meant to me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;audio controls=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;/files/Nic.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re curious about the things I mention in that audio, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.smallfire.org/vauxpage1.html&#34;&gt;Vaux&amp;rsquo;s page on smallfire.org&lt;/a&gt; or explore &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vaux.net/services-archive&#34;&gt;Vaux&amp;rsquo;s archive&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rate of Change Part 3: Intention and Habit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/04/16/rate-of-change-part-3-intention-and-habit</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/04/16/rate-of-change-part-3-intention-and-habit</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Intention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I secretly hate this word. Most of the time I see it used it is referring to some ideal where every decision is cognitively aligned with some higher purpose, those decisions are always correct and time is never wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, intentionality and attention are closely related and frequently conflated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my purposes what I mean by intentionality is most closely related to will. We intend to do something and we do that thing, as opposed to the easier thing, or the more short-sighted thing, or the more immediately gratifying thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to remember that we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t behave in certain ways if we didn&amp;rsquo;t secretly enjoy it. Be it stuffing our face with unhealthy foods or getting involved in a dramatic Facebook thread, it takes a strong will (or a life changing experience) to overcome behaviors that are contrary to our intent. (However I will be the first to advocate for a healthy hedonism in life.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tmcm.com/tmcm/i-wonder-whats-on-tv/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/03/tv.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;I wonder what&#39;s on TV&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of biological reasons for this and I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to explore them right now. From a more philosophical perspective, Viktor Frankl would say that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&amp;amp;v=MmKta5tymPY&#34;&gt;our will to pleasure and our will power come from a frustrated will to meaning&lt;/a&gt;, which I frequently conflate with intentionality for my own purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meaning/calling/will/intentionality&amp;hellip;they all describe different characteristics of the self that we all accept as existent{% fn_ref 1 %} but have a hard time capturing practically either emotionally or intellectually. But it is the kind of thing &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/RYlCVwxoL_g?t=10s&#34;&gt;we know when we see it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Habit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, if we will ourselves to do something long enough, it becomes habit and our &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Self_control#As_a_limited_resource&#34;&gt;tired will&lt;/a&gt; can take a breather (before starting in on the next thing). I have a long-standing and slightly overly-obsessive interest in meaning and identity formation, but also with habit formation and behavior modification; and specifically in regards to the latter, technological tools that intend to help us change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before tools{% fn_ref 2 %}, however, are simply techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is quantification; keeping track of the behavior you want to change. It works for a variety of reasons&amp;ndash;by drawing our attention to the issue in question, by illuminating facts about ourselves we otherwise would not see&amp;ndash;and it probably works for a variety of non-obvious reasons as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will point you to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://quantifiedself.com/&#34; title=&#34;A place for people interested in self-tracking to gather, share knowledge and experiences, and discover resources.&#34;&gt;Quantified Self&lt;/a&gt; website as a rather complete and always expanding compendium of information on the subject. I will also point you to this video, which has a much more personal take on the same subject:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/31401743&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;281&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other really important technique is accountability. This one is well known, but I have found this one thing to be helpful: don&amp;rsquo;t bother setting up accountability agreements with people particularly close to you{% fn_ref 3 %} and, if possible, arrange to be held accountable by a person whose primary interaction with you is around said accountability. Trainer, coach, therapist, pastor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another form of accountability is the use of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.beeminder.com/akrasia/&#34;&gt;commitment device&lt;/a&gt;, however I find they are best used in conjunction with&amp;ndash;not as a replacement for&amp;ndash;good old-fashioned human accountability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other techniques include a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ulysses_pact&#34;&gt;Ulysses pact&lt;/a&gt; (really a specific kind of commitment device) (refer also to &lt;a href=&#34;http://bustr.me/post/18441500095/why-loss-aversion-isnt-a-great-behavior-change-tool&#34;&gt;this commentary&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aversion_therapy&#34;&gt;aversion therapy&lt;/a&gt; and a host of others. In fact there are tons of good books on this subject that I should probably have read before writing a few paragraphs on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tmcm.com/tmcm/faster-shes-gaining/&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/04/faster.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Faster!&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% footnotes %}
  {% fn Um, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=sam+harris+free+will&#34;&gt;or not&lt;/a&gt;. %}
  {% fn Of which there are many, and I will discuss my favorites in a later post. %}
  {% fn The difference between holding someone accountable and nagging them is largely contextual. %}
{% endfootnotes%}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/03/21/rate-of-change-part-2/&#34;&gt;Hard Work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: Trust, Humility, Balance and Sleep&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rate of Change, Part 2: Hard Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/03/21/rate-of-change-part-2-hard-work</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/03/21/rate-of-change-part-2-hard-work</guid>
      <description>

&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/C31NaEoD3WI?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Industry{% fn_ref 1 %}&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat obvious when sitting at one&amp;rsquo;s computer writing or reading a blog post but much harder to own in a way that matters when making moment-by-moment decisions about how to spend one&amp;rsquo;s time and structure one&amp;rsquo;s life: industry is the key to most measurements of success or even lasting, life-affirming change. I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out exactly how to magically make my incredibly lazy bones start working hard every day, but I&amp;rsquo;ve come across a few concepts that seem to be key. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deliberatism.com/blog/forget-self-improvement/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; has it just right, but these parts rang true:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-help books and workshops arm us with ways to trick ourselves into doing things we perhaps should, but generally don’t want, to do. I ask whether this lack of will might actually be the universe trying to tell us something? What if the missing part of the puzzle is not a lack of willpower, but instead a lack of love?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deliberatism.com/blog/seeking-passion/&#34; title=&#34;Seeking Passion&#34;&gt;later observes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to find something you love, you may need to change your search criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding an endeavor that fulfills you, is like finding a good friend or life-partner. It doesn’t “happen” to you, nor does it arrive with an announcement. Instead, it presents itself quietly and develops over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow Dallas technology entreprenaur Garrett Dimon recently referred to &lt;a href=&#34;http://garrettdimon.com/post/13601971410/tenacity&#34;&gt;tenacity&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is that on the surface, we only see the success. We don’t see the work that went into achieving the success. We see the culmination rather than the 10 or even 20 years that went into getting there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hours they put in. The family events they missed. The vacations cut short. The travel. The times they were borderline bankrupt. The career-ending injuries that didn’t end their career. The nights they were homeless. The amount of bet-the-company decisions they made. The uncertainty they live through. The fear of letting down hundreds or thousands of employees. The mornings of waking up at 5am and practicing in freezing cold weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Attention&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ability to focus on the task at hand is vitally important to industry and increasingly difficult to achieve in our ever-connected, distractions-at-our-fingertips world. My inspiration in this area is my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9D-4WKqjZR4&#34;&gt;grandfather&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/9D-4WKqjZR4?rel=0start=240&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve thought often about how he was able to maintain focus the way he did. I&amp;rsquo;ve blamed the internet and other circumstances for my own focus issues. But in the end I think he really was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ol6VYp0naYA&#34;&gt;simply that enthralled and engaged with the things he worked on&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ol6VYp0naYA?rel=0&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to observe how my focus changes as I context switch between the (still far too many) things I have chosen to do: cycling, music, coding, writing. Sunday I was in the studio and this week I find myself stopping to more intentionally listen to the music I normally play just to drown out my coworker&amp;rsquo;s conversations. I find myself contemplating my next record, what songs need to be learned, which people need to be recruited. &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/03/20/son-lux-live/&#34;&gt;I find myself blown away by new music&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;ndash;mysteriously&amp;ndash;crosses my desk during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems that one of the ways to succeed despite all the distractions and context-switching required by modern, connected life is to be able to focus quickly, and on the right things. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve said this exact thing before, and while I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find that post in the archives, I &lt;a href=&#34;http://2005.danielsjourney.com/categories/attention/&#34;&gt;have quoted and written a lot about attention in the past&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But John Lilly recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://john.jubjubs.net/2012/03/02/intentionality/&#34;&gt;stated something close to what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m coming to view intentionality, depth of thought and connection, and the power to focus as the central developmental challenges of our society today. We&amp;rsquo;re going through an incredibly rapid transformation into an always connected, real-time, perma-entertained, ever stimulated world&amp;ndash;and it&amp;rsquo;s becoming clear to me that, somewhat ironically, it&amp;rsquo;s the people who can take advantage of all of that, while also ultimately staying within themselves, will be the ones who make the most profound and positive changes in our world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us, however, especially those who were not born into the Internet age, will continue to struggle with the many tools of distraction at our fingertips, particularly when we find so many things so &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.danpink.com/archives/2012/02/how-to-say-no-especially-to-things-you-want-to-do&#34;&gt;very interesting&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now inhabit an environment (at least in much of the developed world) of abundant options and boundless, inexpensive information. That has triggered our dopamine-seeking instincts to pile too much onto our professional plates — which in turn has produced an entire infrastructure to help us avoid gorging ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe the trick is to just relax and somehow find ways to be productive despite ourselves. Web and game developer extroidinare Shaun Inman &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2012/3/19/2822626/5-minutes-on-the-verge-shaun-inman&#34;&gt;recently confessed&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that I [stay focused]. I&amp;rsquo;m kind of all over the place, with my attention split between web apps, iOS games and apps, and Safari extensions. I&amp;rsquo;m not especially disciplined. I use plain old text files for todo lists. I try to limit my time on Twitter and in my inbox. If I feel my focus waning, I let it wane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that key ingredient of love comes up again as he concludes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curiosity or that unpleasant feeling of leaving something unfinished usually draws me back to a problem or task before too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The potential down side of extreme focus is the possibility of concentrating on the &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt; things and missing out on what is &lt;em&gt;truly&lt;/em&gt; important. More on that in future installments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% footnotes %}
  {% fn It is difficult to keep a post about hard work and concentration from becoming just a list of aphorisms. My hope for this piece was if I were to at least just write out some of my struggles it would help me find ways through them (and perhaps make for more interesting reading for those patient enough to continue with this series). I ended up&amp;ndash;somewhat ironically&amp;ndash;down many rabbit holes in the process. I hope I have compiled what I&amp;rsquo;ve found in an intelligent manner. %}
{% endfootnotes%}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/03/15/rate-of-change-part-1/&#34;&gt;Contentment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up: Intention and Habit&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rate of Change, Part 1: Contentment</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/03/15/rate-of-change-part-1-contentment</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/03/15/rate-of-change-part-1-contentment</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I started March out with great ambitions and plans, all of which I have failed at. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about that failure and how to adjust&amp;ndash;either my plans or my behavior. I started, but never finished, a blog post about those goals. It said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that [these goals] continued to come up as two things I wanted to do and deciding that I would commit the time and resources to doing them are two very different things. In addition, they are frequently at odds with one another, especially when fit in around established goals like maintaining a happy family life and supporting it through growing a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://extrasauce.com&#34;&gt;business&lt;/a&gt;. In fact those established goals could take all of my time if I allowed them to. I&amp;rsquo;ve alternatively viewed additional goals as selfish or as sanity-retention. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure which they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I am two weeks later and not only did I not make any progress on either of those goals, but I&amp;rsquo;m doing less work towards them than I did in February, when I was just flirting with them while going about my everyday life. Always the armchair psychologist, I want to figure out why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;A Tale of Two Bike Commutes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I bike commute to work&amp;ndash;and my car battery died while we were in Oklahoma so I&amp;rsquo;ve taken it as opportunity to force the habit&amp;ndash;I normally take one of two routes. &lt;a href=&#34;http://g.co/maps/gebdd&#34;&gt;One route&lt;/a&gt; involves riding down two of the most affluent streets in Dallas. A quick survey on Zillow indicates a median home price north of one million dollars. &lt;a href=&#34;http://g.co/maps/nc74t&#34;&gt;The other route&lt;/a&gt; (just a handful of blocks to the southeast) takes me through a more economically depressed and ethnically diverse part of town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When riding the former route I frequently wonder, &amp;ldquo;What do these people do to make so much money?&amp;rdquo;{% fn_ref 1 %} One time I arrived home and announced to Carissa, &amp;ldquo;I have a new goal to be eccentric and work from our house on &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Swiss_Avenue,_Dallas,_Texas&#34;&gt;Swiss&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter route inspires me to be happy with less. I see people outside of their homes, talking with their neighbors. Old men give me puzzled looks from their front porch chairs. There are run-down houses and cluttered lawns, but there are also properties that are meticulously maintained. They communicate a level of care that doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on financial agency. They have local markets they walk to. Their children play up and down the street. One time I arrived home and told Carissa, &amp;ldquo;All the stuff new urbanists are trying to create, these people have!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I covet the resources, space and comfort on display along the &amp;ldquo;rich&amp;rdquo; route, something deeper calls from the alternate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Contentment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always struggled with the balance between contentment and drive. I spent so much of my life discontent and striving towards some unknowable happiness that when I arrived at it &lt;a href=&#34;http://themusicgroup.org/track/what-am-i-supposed-to-do&#34;&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what to do&lt;/a&gt;. More recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://2010.danielsjourney.com&#34;&gt;events&lt;/a&gt; then threw all ideas about contentment and happiness&amp;ndash;or even trust in a higher purpose&amp;ndash;to the wind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/03/calvin_history.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Calvin and Hobbes: History is the fiction we invent to persuade ourselves that events are knowable and that life has order and direction.&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But lately I have felt like I&amp;rsquo;m getting closer to this content-but-improving way-of-being. I&amp;rsquo;ve always admired people who seem totally content and yet continue to work hard and produce amazing things or live notable lives. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wayne_Coyne&#34;&gt;Wayne Coyne&lt;/a&gt; comes to mind. I love the documentary &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Fearless_Freaks&#34;&gt;Fearless Freaks&lt;/a&gt; mostly because it highlights so clearly the character qualities he has that have made him so successful&amp;ndash;mostly the ability and willingness to consistently work hard over a long period of time. My &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2012/03/10/stephen-wolfram-the-personal-analytics-of-my-life/&#34;&gt;recent post about Stephen Wolfram&amp;rsquo;s personal data tracking&lt;/a&gt; also accents these qualities of hard work and consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was originally going to be one post, but as it became longer and longer I decided to break it up. Hopefully I continue with the rest of it. Next up: Industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;{% footnotes %}
  {% fn Back-of-the-napkin calculations: a one million dollar house with $28,600/yr property taxes (based on an example on Swiss) means costs of $74k/yr which requires an income of (with housing being 28%) a little over $264k/yr (that is not counting insurance or maintenance costs). So sure, there are plenty of professions where someone could make that much (or more likely a double income family could make that much) but for most of us an income in that range (consistently over 30 years) is unrealistic. %}
{% endfootnotes%}&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
