<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Nonlinear on kieranhealy.org </title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/nonlinear/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Kieran Healy</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) KIeran Healy.</rights>
    <updated>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stephen Wolfram -- The Personal Analytics of My Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/03/10/stephen-wolfram----the-personal-analytics-of-my-life</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Mar 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/03/10/stephen-wolfram----the-personal-analytics-of-my-life</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/03/outgoing-mail-diurnal-image.png&#34; alt=&#34;{quote}Here&#39;s a plot with a dot showing the time of each of the third of a million emails I&#39;ve sent since 1989&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.stephenwolfram.com/2012/03/the-personal-analytics-of-my-life/&#34;&gt;I have what is probably one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest collections of personal data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;my consistent experience has been that the more routine I can make the basic practical aspects of my life, the more I am able to be energetic&amp;ndash;and spontaneous&amp;ndash;about intellectual and other things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;in time I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to being able to ask Wolfram|Alpha all sorts of things about my life and times&amp;ndash;and have it immediately generate reports about them. Not only being able to act as an adjunct to my personal memory, but also to be able to do automatic computational history&amp;ndash;explaining how and why things happened&amp;ndash;and then making projections and predictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog post crossed my desk from an unexpected source and I was pleased to have found it and enthralled by its content. One of the things I was most taken with was how it is a record of such undeniable industriousness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cows Got Raptured</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/01/11/the-cows-got-raptured</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2012 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2012/01/11/the-cows-got-raptured</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/files/2012/01/cow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Cow Clicker Wired Article Screenshot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hi Ian,&amp;rdquo; writes one. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that the Cowpocalypse has happened and users have to pay to see their cow. Do you have a goal or timeframe of when this will be set back to normal?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no way to pay to see your cow,&amp;rdquo; replied the designer. &amp;ldquo;The cows got raptured.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.danielsjourney.com/2011/04/15/shit-crayons/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve written about Ian Bogost before&lt;/a&gt;, and recently two excellent articles recapping the history of his Cow Clicker Facebook game crossed by desk (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marco.org/&#34;&gt;via Marco&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;a href=&#34;http://kotaku.com/5846080/the-life+changing-20-rightward+facing-cow&#34;&gt;The Life-Changing $20 Rightward-Facing Cow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bogost&amp;rsquo;s years of research and writing on how games could affect perspective and behavior prized design wisdom and a deep understanding of context and of other media. Yet suddenly there was an explosion of investment in gamification startups eager to tack game mechanics onto things like check-in apps. The intersection of games and real life was suddenly a very trendy thing, and a new legion of spokespeople emerged to simplify, systematize and mass-market it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wired.com/magazine/2011/12/ff_cowclicker/all/1&#34;&gt;The Curse of Cow Clicker: How a Cheeky Satire Became a Videogame Hit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To some industry stalwarts, the gamification craze looks a lot like Cow Clicker—mindlessly deploying gaming’s most superficial and addictive features, such as leaderboards and badges, without providing the underlying experience that gives them meaning. Bogost himself made this argument at a gamification conference, during a talk called Gamification Is Bullshit, in which he suggested an alternate term, exploitationware. That, he said, represents the true mission of gamifiers: to use game mechanics to cynically ensnare their customers, much as Cow Clicker had unwittingly hooked its prey—including, as it turned out, Bogost himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;both are worth the time to read, especially if you&amp;rsquo;re even moderately interested in games and social software, or even just social psychology.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shit Crayons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/04/15/shit-crayons</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/04/15/shit-crayons</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bogost.com/images/content/writing/cowrant22.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bogost.com/images/content/writing/cowrant22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bogost.com/writing/shit_crayons.shtml&#34;&gt;Ian Bogost makes a scathing critique of social games&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years ago, Chaim Gingold gave us the useful concept of the Magic
Crayon. A magic crayon is a tool that facilitates creativity in a way that
wouldn&amp;rsquo;t otherwise be possible. A magic crayon lets its users breathe life
into things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some would like to think that all crayons are magic ones. That just any old
thing can conjure. But that&amp;rsquo;s not true. The magic crayon has a shadow side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some barriers are benign, but others are insidious&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspirations like that are not magic crayons, but shit crayons&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if creativity comes from constraint, there&amp;rsquo;s constraint and there&amp;rsquo;s
incarceration. A despot in a sorcerer&amp;rsquo;s hat does not deserve praise for
inciting desperate resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is too short to make shitty software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/03/15/life-is-too-short-to-make-shitty-software</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/03/15/life-is-too-short-to-make-shitty-software</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The other day I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What we do is make software. And software is best made by humans who
understand each other (and by extension understand the people who use their
software). Unless they’re miraculously made up of such humans, organizations
make shitty software.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I just had some more thoughts about that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make or work on software that sucks anymore. Life is too short
to work on something that is shit to begin with. Just because a piece of
software improves your process or workflow over the paper version you used in
the 80&amp;rsquo;s does not mean that it is not shitty software. Just because a piece of
software is better than its competition in X, Y and Z ways does not mean that
it is not shitty software. Just because a piece of software just like its
competition except in that one way you need it to be different does not mean
it&amp;rsquo;s not shitty software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we are to take our craft seriously, to consider ourselves worthy of our
work, to join in a lineage of artisans and, most importantly, enjoy ourselves
while we work and work in a way worthy of the life we have been given, then we
must make software that is a delight to use, that makes our customer&amp;rsquo;s lives
not just seem to be easier, but actually brings them joy in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not good enough to add the features they want or fix the bug they are
complaining about or improve the workflow that is still&amp;ndash;despite your
wonderful technology&amp;ndash;a total mess and waste of their precious time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is most of our &amp;ldquo;users&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;and what a terrible word for these
people, these people we have a (for the most part) unseeing yet terribly
intimate relationship with&amp;hellip;but &amp;ldquo;customer&amp;rdquo; is also a horrible word! A
customer is someone you exchange money for goods with, not someone who
interacts with your product every day and alternatively praises and curses you
in abstentia, who scours the internet for advice on how to use your product,
who navigates some joyless &amp;ldquo;customer service&amp;rdquo; experience in order to better
use your shitty product. Usually, the only way the term &amp;ldquo;user&amp;rdquo; applies to
those who use our software is in its similarity to &amp;ldquo;drug user&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;they have no
choice but to use our product, despite a more abundant life calling out to
them from outside the boundaries of this myopic experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;The problem is most of The People Using Our Software are within an even
larger set of boundaries: rules, expectations, norms, mores, groupthink,
culture, ignorance&amp;hellip;part of the reason we make shitty software is because we
live in a frequently shitty world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other day I was riding in a group ride on the service road along I-30 in
east Dallas and I was looking at all the shit along the road there and I
thought of this video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/1465284?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&#34; width=&#34;1279&#34; height=&#34;719&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want this to be a Jerry Maguire mission statement, I don&amp;rsquo;t want this
to be a Fight Club deconstruction of society. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make any more
movie references. I just want to make great software and I want to be
empowered to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to proof this post. I&amp;rsquo;m just going to put it out there as
it is, incomplete and probably more than a little incoherent&amp;hellip;but I&amp;rsquo;d love to
hear what you have to say about this, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Writing is Good</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/03/12/good-writing-is-good</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/03/12/good-writing-is-good</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maciej Ceglowski is one of the proprietors of &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinboard.in/&#34;&gt;Pinboard&lt;/a&gt; and also &lt;a href=&#34;http://idlewords.com/&#34;&gt;an
amazing writer&lt;/a&gt;. His recent &lt;a href=&#34;http://pinboard.in/blog/173/&#34;&gt;post describing technical aspects of the great
exodus from Delicious (to Pinboard)&lt;/a&gt; has too many gems to capture them all,
but here are a couple in case you need convincing when it comes to reading
technical blog posts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before this moment, our relationship to Delicious had been that of a tick to
an elephant. We were a niche site and in the course of eighteen months had
siphoned off about six thousand users from our massive competitor, a pace I
was was very happy with and hoped to sustain through 2011. But now the Senior
Vice President for Bad Decisions at Yahoo had decided to give us a little
help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had always prided ourself on being a minimalist website. But the
experience for new users now verged on Zen-like. After paying the signup fee,
a new user would upload her delicious bookmarks, see a message that the upload
was pending, and&amp;hellip; that was it. It was possible to add bookmarks by hand, but
there was no tag cloud, no tag auto-completion, no suggested tags for URLs,
the aggregate bookmark counts on the profile page were all wrong, and there
was no way to search bookmarks less than a day old. This was a lot to ask of
people who were already skittish about online bookmarking. A lot of my time
was spent reassuring new users that their data was safe and that their money
was not winging its way to the Cayman Islands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That post led me back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://idlewords.com/&#34;&gt;idlewords.com&lt;/a&gt; to which I was already
&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&#34;&gt;subscribed&lt;/a&gt;, it turns out, but I clicked a random link and read &lt;a href=&#34;http://idlewords.com/2005/04/dabblers_and_blowhards.htm&#34;&gt;Dabblers
and Blowhards&lt;/a&gt; a brilliant critique of a book I have actually read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly hard to pin Paul Graham down on the nature of the special
bond he thinks hobbyist programmers and painters share. In his essays he tends
to flit from metaphor to metaphor like a butterfly, never pausing long enough
to for a suspicious reader to catch up with his chloroform jar. The closest he
comes to a clear thesis statement is at the beginning &amp;ldquo;Hackers and Painters&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;[O]f all the different types of people I&amp;rsquo;ve known, hackers and painters
are among the most alike. What hackers and painters have in common is that
they&amp;rsquo;re both makers.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To which I&amp;rsquo;d add, what hackers and painters don&amp;rsquo;t have in common is
everything else. The fatuousness of the parallel becomes obvious if you think
for five seconds about what computer programmers and painters actually do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Computer programmers cause a machine to perform a sequence of
transformations on electronically stored data.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Painters apply colored goo to cloth using animal hairs tied to a stick.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;it goes on in similar fashion, you should go read it, especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve
read &lt;em&gt;Hackers &amp;amp; Painters&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New danielsjourney</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/01/22/new-danielsjourney</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/01/22/new-danielsjourney</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Usually a redesign of a one-page site of mine doesn&amp;rsquo;t warrant a blog post, but
this story is a little bit more interesting, mostly because of the work it
built on. I haven&amp;rsquo;t really told the story of a design before. I&amp;rsquo;m curious how
this will pan out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://danielsjourney.com&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://farm6.static.flickr.com/5087/5376146429_9897396ba7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was in my RSS reader last night after an ill-advised after-dinner coffee and
saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://weightshift.com/memo/created/the-personal-page/&#34;&gt;Naz&amp;rsquo;s post on Weightshift about the personal page&lt;/a&gt;&amp;hellip;meme? Can we call
it that? I had long since moved to a single-serving homepage w/ some text and
an image. In the meantime about.me made it a big deal. (Nevermind that Dallas-
based &lt;a href=&#34;http://magnt.com/&#34;&gt;Magnt&lt;/a&gt; had a better offering since long ago.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let&amp;rsquo;s face it, Naz&amp;rsquo;s, and his imitators&amp;rsquo;, looked better. And most
importantly, he &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/weightshift/The-Personal-Page&#34;&gt;posted the source on Github&lt;/a&gt;. That meant that seconds
later I had &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dealingwith/The-Personal-Page&#34;&gt;my own copy of his source&lt;/a&gt; on my computer and started
replacing his images and text with my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It used a script called backstretch to position and size the image, also on
Github, which I also &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dealingwith/jquery-backstretch&#34;&gt;forked and modified&lt;/a&gt; for my uses. Since I had already
decided to use a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/carissabyers/sets/72157625162248858/with/5081188250/&#34;&gt;wedding picture&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to try and at least create two
layers so the field grass could superimpose the text box. The original
backstretch script could only accomodate one image which it threw far into the
back of the document model. That was easily fixed in just &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dealingwith/jquery-backstretch/commit/e7db01009effab5e5fe8d514f886c296911d6917&#34;&gt;a couple lines of
code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That got me thinking about the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/404&#34;&gt;awesome Github 404 page&lt;/a&gt;. Maybe I could
&lt;a href=&#34;http://webdev.stephband.info/parallax.html&#34;&gt;parallax&lt;/a&gt; the grass! Well I tried applying the parallax plugin to the
elements in question and no dice. I tried a new page that didn&amp;rsquo;t use
backstretch and applying the parallax plugin there&amp;ndash;still no dice. Last night
I decided to stick to just the two layers&amp;ndash;if someone had a window sized just
right, they would notice the grass popping up over the bottom of the box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course this morning I couldn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GcZ8Gz0rDtw&#34;&gt;let it be&lt;/a&gt;! I read most of the parallax
code and while it was pretty much what I expected, its need to accomodate for
all manner of circumstances made it overly complex to just copy and paste to
fit my needs. I ended up just hand-coding some &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dealingwith/The-Personal-Page/blob/master/script.js&#34;&gt;simple code&lt;/a&gt; that moves
the grass in the direction you move your mouse, after doing a single left-
right sway once on page load just for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m far too pleased with the end result. Now I am considering trying to get
the foreground grass to actually bend as it moves&amp;hellip;in the meantime if you
haven&amp;rsquo;t you can &lt;a href=&#34;http://danielsjourney.com&#34;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WWIC: Why Wasn&#39;t I Consulted</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/01/06/wwic-why-wasnt-i-consulted</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2011/01/06/wwic-why-wasnt-i-consulted</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ftrain.com/wwic.html&#34;&gt;Ftrain: The Web Is a Customer Service Medium&lt;/a&gt;. Paul Ford has been writing
on the web longer than most and as usual this piece is excellent:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What sums it up best, to me, is this image published on the blog Kotaku (if
you know where the image originates please let me know). The image was posted
as a comment on a blog post linking to an article about British computer-
industry millionaire Clive Sinclair marrying a younger woman. Here is the
image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://cache.gawker.com/assets/images/comment/9/2010/04/4238e5f9f0a180cf4f11b94fd1c1a032/340x.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://cache.gawker.com/assets/images/comment/9/2010/04/4238e5f9f0a180cf4f11b94fd1c1a032/340x.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider what that cartoon &lt;em&gt;means&lt;/em&gt; in that context: It implies that the
commenter feels—with some irony and self-awareness, I&amp;rsquo;m sure—that his opinion,
in some way, is relevant to the question of whether Clive Sinclair should
marry a particular woman. This is, for many obvious reasons, completely
insane. And yet there was an image already sketched and available to that
commenter so that he could express this exact sentiment of &lt;em&gt;choosing not to be
outraged at a situation he read about on the Internet&lt;/em&gt;. WWIC in action.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tableau</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2010/12/21/tableau</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2010 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Kieran Healy</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/archives/2010/12/21/tableau</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://berglondon.com/blog/2010/12/16/thursday-links-a-drawerful-of-photographs-fictional-logos-flashy-advertising-and-space/&#34;&gt;BERG&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;ldquo;John Kestner’s &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnkestner.com/tableau/&#34;&gt;Tableau&lt;/a&gt; is a nightstand that drops photos
it &amp;lsquo;sees&amp;rsquo; in its Twitter feed into its drawer, to be discovered by its owner.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://player.vimeo.com/video/17280777?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitAllowFullScreen mozallowfullscreen allowFullScreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/17280777&#34;&gt;Tableau: physical email&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/jkestner&#34;&gt;John Kestner&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Kestner is part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://eco.media.mit.edu/&#34;&gt;Information Ecology team at the MIT Media
Lab&lt;/a&gt;, so of course &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/dealingwith/status/17031471495647232&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to gush a bit&lt;/a&gt;, but check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/jkestner&#34;&gt;some videos
of his other projects&lt;/a&gt; as well as &lt;a href=&#34;http://coloured.net/john/portfolio/&#34;&gt;the rest of his portfolio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m particarly interested in things like the &lt;a href=&#34;http://coloured.net/john/portfolio/daydar/&#34;&gt;Daydar personal productivity
framework&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
